What I have in my hands here now is a milk snake, this particular guy is part of the Colubridae family as all milk snakes are.
There's two different types of snake, Boyd's and Colubridae's in the reptile family.
The Colubridae's tend to be a thinner, faster, snake than the Boyd's are.
This one in particular is trying very hard to do some mimicry coloration and look a awful lot like a coral snake which is a highly venomous snake in the South America type region.
The coral snake has a similar color and pattern, perhaps you've heard the rhyme "red touches yellow kills a fellow, red touches black a venom lack".
This is in response to the colors of the coral snake verses the milk snake.
The coral snake's bands are red, yellow, black, as opposed to red, black, yellow, on this particular milk snake.
Now again, any snake in the wild should be treated as a dangerous snake until properly identified.
Some coral snakes don't follow that coloration rule so always be careful when you're ever handling a snake like this out of the wild but I know this is a milk snake, it's been a captive born snake.
Usually, these guys are tend to be a little bit flighty though this one's being very, very, well behaved for me.
They get about four to six feet at adult size and like I said tend to be a little nervous but this guy's being very well behaved.
Usually, they're kind of quick to poop on you when you handle them or to try to run away but this one is being very, very, nice today.
Other things to note on Colubridae's, they don't have the heat pits like Boyd's do and pythons particular.
There's that heat sensing apparatus isn't there, they don't sense heat as well.
There much more of a smelling snake with that tongue and the Jacobson's organ like we talked about before.